**Software Developer** 

Orlando FL | (407) 283-4884 | bminaya2@gmail.com

LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

### Technical Skills

• HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, JQuery, Python, Django, ReactJS, Express, NodeJS, MongoDB, API, GIT, Tailwind

## **Professional Summary**

Motivated and determined Full Stack Developer with a passion for front-end web development and being able to satisfy the need for creativity through UI/UX design. Expertise in object-oriented programming technologies such as JavaScript, React library, and MongoDB databases. Strong ability to learn and implement new technology methods while prioritizing user experience. Excited to grow as a software developer and join a fast-paced organization where my technical skills and creative thinking are useful.

## **Projects**

## Getaway Trips | Front End Application | Github | Live Site

Single-page application formatted to mimic websites for booking vacations, similar to Airbnb.

- Re-engineered landing page using JSX to keep files organized and understandable with large pieces of code
- Equipped with Node Project Manager (NPM) for assistance in installing several packages and resolving its countless dependencies
- Ensured website is responsive and compatible with various screen sizes for maximizing a good user experience and easy management

### Good Reads | Full Stack Application | Github | Live Site

MERN-based app imitating a user-friendly book library executing CRUD operations

- Designed application end-to-end using MERN to develop powerful and scalable web applications
- Relied on MongoDB, an open source NoSQL database to design RESTful backend routes allowing to recognize the specific resource involved in an interaction between components
- Upgraded re-existing application with React improving performance using Virtual DOM making this framework fast and reliable

## **Experience**

#### Front-End Developer Intern | Outspoke.io | May 2022 - Current

- Collaborated with developer team using Github version control for coordinated output
- Developed application utilizing React, Express, NodeJS, and Mongo Atlas to further assist optimization in supply chain fragility

#### Assembler/Production | Daniels Manufacturing Corporation | Feb 2022 - Current

- Contributed to a team of 30 individuals while maintaining open communication resulting in successful outcomes
- Promoted within the first month in the company for exceeding goals and supporting company culture

#### **Team Lead** | Universal Nissan | October 2020 - July 2021

- Led a team of 5 individuals by effectively delegating tasks to ensure organization and support company goals
- Met customer needs and maximized customer satisfaction rates by providing professional and friendly customer service

# **Education and Training**

Mern Full Stack Web Development Certificate | 2021

Coding Dojo

Front End Training | 2019-2020

Treehouse

**Associate of Arts - General Studies Program** | 2018-2020

Valencia College